women, they don't want to stay at home
when you pull them. They just want
flexible working hours and flexible
working conditions like you have. And I
think we should all advocate for that.
It's not one or the other. But when you
sit here and you go, you'll be more
fulfilled doing this and spend all your
time doing that. We would love for you
to leave the public eye and go focus on
what makes you fulfilled. Okay.
Hi, my name is Candace Owens. I am a
podcaster, a mother, a wife, and also
the author of the upcoming book, Make
Him a Sandwich. And today I am
surrounded by 20 feminists.
My first claim is that the sexual
revolution has devalued women and made
them infinitely less happy.
Hi. Hello.
Hi. Hi. I'm Somaya. Somaya. Nice to meet
you. I'm Candace. Nice to meet you, too.
So my question for you is statistics
show that 60% of women who are murdered
are murdered by their intimate partners
murdered by someone that they are in
close relations with. Uh that's
according to the UN uh from 2023. Yeah.
So how is it that you know women are so
valued you know quotequote in the home
and yet that's the place where they're
at the most danger? Okay. So I'm not
sure what that has to do with the sexual
revolution. Right. sexual revolution.
The sexual revolution gave I'm happy to
answer it. I'm just saying that, you
know, if you brought in that statistic,
you are more likely in general just to
be murdered by somebody, you know. So,
of course, but men are much less likely
to be murdered by, you know, their
That's not true.
Yeah, I'm sure. Because men are less
likely to be murdered by women. Full
stop. That's Yeah, exact. So, that
statistic makes sense to me. I'm still
not sure how this correlates to whether
or not sexual revolution increased
women's ability to leave the house,
women's ability to control their own
reproductive capabilities, women's
ability to, you know, control their own
like capacity within the workforce in
regards to their own sexual capacity. So
it is the very fact that like the sexual
revolution happened that made our access
to the workplace much more or or just
the public sphere in general much more
easy. So like without the sexual
revolution women would be much more
confined to the place where they're at
the most danger. Isn't that true? Uh so
you think that just so I'm trying to
understand your argument here. You think
that if we didn't have the sexual
revolution less women or more women
would be murdered? Are you saying that
women are more women would be murdered
for sure? Okay. Um, I disagree with
that. I still don't think it has
anything to do with the claim that women
are infinitely less happy because of the
sexual revolution, which has you
probably less happy if you're being
murdered. Oh,
anyone. Okay. Yeah. I don't Okay. Okay.
There is definitely a correlation
between personal relationships and
domestic violence. And just to be clear,
if we're talking about just like a
monogous relationships, the most violent
relationships that are on the books are
between lesbian partners. Yes. When
people are intimately That's not That's
not a true. No, the statistic you're
talking about is people who have faced
domestic violence. Lesbians, yes, are
more likely to have faced domestic
violence, but that's because they
typically came from relationships with
men in which lesbian relationships are
the most violent relationships that we
have on the typically they can fact
check that claim. The point being is
that it's not exactly a stunning
statistic to say that when people are in
relationships period, whether those
relationships are homosexual, whether
they're saying that the sexual Let me
finish. I' I've let you try to explain
how this is correlated to happiness. And
I I don't think it does. I I actually
think you're you're having a different
debate right now. But it Yes,
absolutely. It makes perfect sense that
you are more likely in general when you
are in a relationship because people are
driven by anger by people that they know
whether or not we're talking about
boyfriend and girlfriend, girlfriend and
girlfriend, uh you know, a husband and a
wife, a husband and a husband or a wife
and a wife. Yes, of course, the
instances of domestic violence are going
to take place when you're inside of a
home. But the sexual revolution,
encouraging women to give up their goods
for free, which is what I'm speaking
about, and encouraging men not to marry
these women or to have long-term
relationships, what I am saying is a a
direct contributor to their unhappiness
because women are giving up their goods
for free. And women are now entering the
workplace and that does not actually
make them happy. Okay, pause. Sorry,
you've been voted out by the majority.
Please return to your seat.
Hello. Hi there. How are you? I'm
Candace. Candace, nice to meet you. Nice
to meet you. Um Julian, my pronouns are
they, them. It's very interesting to
think of it when we think about the
gender binary. Um I it's, you know, how
do we place value on human beings in
general? And so when we think about, you
know, placing value that comes from a p
a place of power, right? So I think
let's select like the Victorian era. you
have this dominant group of people
coming from white supremacy deciding who
gets to have um a a a proper status in
the world. And so that is already like
placed taking human beings and devaluing
them. And so what the sexual revolution
did was to help people seek out
empowerment which increased value no
matter the gender. So when it comes to
sexual revolution, let's look at one
contribution is sex education. I'm
actually an educator. I teach uh
sociology and LGBTQ studies and I have
absolutely seen the positive outcome
with the sexual revolution and sex
education and seen people empower
themselves and with that comes uh safety
when it comes to um decreasing STI uh
abuse uh sexual assault again people get
to empower themselves of all genders and
I know earlier you mentioned about uh
violence amongst uh lesbians and safic
community which I do identify within all
genders can be subjected to violence
that was the point I was making. So, I
wasn't sure of how her claim was
relating to what we were talking about,
whether or not it makes people happy or
unhappy. Relationships are obviously a
ground where there can be violence. I
guess I could just wrap it up by saying
like if we all have access to like sex
education through the incredible work of
feminists through the sex sexual
revolution, we are able to gain access
to information and gain skills to create
an equitable society and egalitarian
within our relationships, whether it be
platonic or romantic. I'm so grateful
for those feminists who have fought for
us so we can gain those spaces and
create a healthier society. Okay. Are
you a believer in the government doing
everything that it can to make people
happy? So when it comes as someone that
teaches in the public sector, um I
understand the concern when it comes
about what is a teacher, you know, what
kind of information they're providing to
the students. Um I do believe that we as
a teacher, I should be able to give that
sort of information. Again, I teach
college students. One of my claims is I
believe that we should mandate uh uh sex
education amongst college students. Um
so yes, I do want the state I would like
the government to give us those
resources so we can implement that
curriculum. Okay. Would you are you
consider yourself a feminist? I'm
assuming a queer feminist. There's
there's diff there's variations, right?
What is a queer feminist as opposed to a
feminist? Just so I understand. Well,
like so I heavily believe in queer
theory. So you know the gender binary
that we understand it comes from
colonization. So someone who is mixed
race um family from Mexico you know um
we have the mushes of Mexico which is an
indigenous tribe they believed in gender
fluidity and then you have European
colonizers coming who dismantle that and
now everything that we understand when
it comes to gender is a western lens. So
from a queer you don't even think women
exist. I'm guessing I think everyone
should be empowered to figure out their
identity and explore the language that
best describes themselves. So freedom
America right America freedom and I want
to believe in that when it comes to
identity everyone should have the
freedom to decide how they want to
identify as long as they're not causing
harm. But that's where we get into the
debate. What is harm? So just again to
be clear to go back to this claim we are
debating female happiness. You are
saying you do not identify as a female.
I identify with all gender expressions.
So from masculinity to femininity. I So,
so I'm just saying,
are you just saying that as as a part of
queer theory, you're debating whether or
not women are happier after the se
sexual revolution? I'm just trying to
understand because it seems like you're
debating queer theory as opposed to
female. I believe all genders benefit
from the sexual revolution. You've been
voted out by the majority. Please return
to your seat.
[Music]
Hello, I'm Zena. Zena, very much like
your name. Thank you so much. Nice to
meet you. Can we start with the
beginning? Do you identify as a female?
I identify as a woman. Yeah. Okay.
Right. So, I I do want to like get back
to your premise. You're saying that
women have been devalued, right, by the
sexual revolution. This like kind of
presumes two things. One, that there has
been a loss of worth, right, for women.
So you're saying that women have as
human beings lost worth? Women who prior
to their revol sexual revolution were
worth worth more than women today. I
would say that yes, women have devalued
themselves by becoming overtly sexual.
Uh that's my claim. So I mean also
according to just and and let's not
remove this from the other part of the
claim which that has it has made women
infinitely less happy. Right. So are you
saying but you're saying that according
to you women have been devalued? Not
according to me. Um uh according to the
time in which people are getting
married, how difficult it is for people
to find a partner that's willing to
commit to them. And I think that's in
large part due to the fact that women
are offering sex for free because it was
a main, you know, a major component of
the sexual revolution was this idea. So
a woman's worth is tied to her
sexuality. It's not it's not tied to
Well, absolutely. If you're going to be
having multiple partners, you are going
to be devaluing yourself. I You're worth
less as a human being. Not as a human
being. just, you know, in terms of
trying to have a partnership and a
productive relationship, certainly men
are not going to be clamoring to have a
relationship with somebody when there's
the market is throwing them. A man's
response to your actions is what defines
your worth, right? Yeah. Well, um I
would say that I would argue that at the
what makes women actually happy is
family. So, if you're interrupting, so
just to connect a dots for you, when
women are having sex with multiple
partners, it devalues them for men,
right? For men. So yes men define a
woman's worth. Well, I would say both of
them kind of define one another's worth
because I think the ultimate goal for
people to be happy is actually family.
Okay. So you're saying in all cases a
woman is going to be more fulfilled in
regards to family. Like exactly what I'm
saying and this is going to work in all
cases. You're saying there's no
individual case in which a woman can
feel you know fulfilled without being
tied to other people ina in the case of
I think there could be an exceptional
case for everything. I think there are
exceptional cases. Uh but I think that
if we all start trying to be the
exception as opposed to recognizing the
rule which is that people in life are
more fulfilled when they achieve a
family unit and when they have children,
women in particular especially having
aspiring to children then you are going
to end up with a bunch of people who are
unhappy because your job cannot replace
the feeling of having a family. So what
you're saying is we need to look at
every individual case and see what is
going to fulfill you or what is going to
I guess essentially predict your
happiness more because if we look at for
example the the Nordic countries right
these are countries I'm talking about
like Sweden Denmark right these
countries tend to be like I think in the
past 14 years they've been ranked as the
highest in happiness and marital
satisfaction from women right and we see
that they also have been the most open
in regards to like you know sexual norms
and and you know sexual roles right so
and we also see that there's less rates
of like STDs reported. Um we see um more
um and that's also due to comprehensive
sex education that is pushed in those
countries. So we see that when we and
that's like a direct result of the
sexual revolution, right? So when we're
seeing that direct reports of happiness,
right, we don't have these same rates in
America in these countries that are more
sexually open. Why would we see like
those rates in those type of countries?
So, I think you might be referring to
this sort of mass-produced study that
was a part of like a behavioral science
study which said that women were the
happiest women in the world were women
that were actually unmarried and had
careers. No. Okay. Well, there was
reported happiness. Okay. Sure. I'm
talking about the same thing. It was
reported happiness, but it could be a
different there's tons of studies. The
point being is that in 20 in 2023 there
was this massive scandal where they
recognized that a lot of these studies
that were being produced behavioral
science was proven to be a complete
fraud and they were unable to reproduce
these studies and they also found that
the data had been faked. The data that
we can look at that I think shows and
you can let me know if you agree with
this. If women and under the imagination
of the feminist umbrella were really
unhappy when they were in the home and
then entering the workforce has made
women happier and infinitely feeling
more secure about themselves, we could,
I think, reasonably expect that there
would have been a decrease in suicide
rates amongst women. You would have to
go ahead and show how that correlation,
right, is going to be a direct cause of
women going into the workforce. Okay.
Well, how can we let's measure then you
have to give me a way that we can
measure happiness. How can we measure
happiness? I I would say suicide rates
would be a good thing to look at. Drug,
alcohol consumption would be of course,
right? But we have to we we can say I
can say at this point in society I I
don't think everyone is happy. I think
there's a lot of things that we need to
reconcile to society. That's what I'm
getting at. But we have to look at the
cause, right? Why are are these things
predicted, right? And and for example,
if we talk about men, there are a lot of
things we can look at, right? That um
that you know tend to predetermine
suicide, right? But we can't say, "Oh,
these two things are happening at the
same time. This caused this other
thing." Yes, that's right. But I do
think that we can objectively say that
women who are are committing suicide
rates more than they were in the 1950s.
Like it has it has actually increased
marginally. That's not a sign that the
us entering the workforce suddenly made
us cause of the workforce. We've all
we're also binge binge drinking at a
higher rate. How is this cause of at a
higher rate? How is this cause of
entering? I think women are being put on
a pathway aspirationally. But you're
going to have to You're saying you think
this, right? But where is worth the
cause? Like you're not you're not, you
know, substantiating the claim. You're
saying this is what I think. I'm seeing
two. Okay. Pause. You've been voted out
by the majority. Please return to your
seat. Thank you so much. A great job.
Great job.
[Music]
Hello. Hi. Hi. I'm Nikki. Nice to meet
you. So, when we're talking about the
value of women uh on a societal scale
and how we view each other, right,
when you're devaluing us, you're
objectifying us. And and follow me, I
promise. But rape rates have gone down
by about half in the last 20 years,
right? So,
if you're saying we're less valuable
now, why wouldn't we be suffering at a
higher rate? So is the argument that
you're making, just so I understand,
that because women are giving up sex for
free, they're not being raped. Every
study shows rape is not correlated with
just sexual gratification. It is a power
structure. Okay? So it is about
objectifying and abusing women when you
rape them, not about whether or not you
want sex. What I am saying is that women
are less objectified.
So therefore, we are being raped less.
Okay. So, you think that in today's
society, cuz this is this is pretty wild
for me. In the 1950s, you're saying
women were more objectified than today
in the land of only fans, the Kardashian
clan, and women that are essentially
putting up their boobs and butts for
free on Instagram. You're saying we are
now we've finally have achieved less
objectification where women can't even
get onto an advertising. you can't even
advertise a bag without them having to
be naked in order for them to get a
career as a model. You're saying, "Oh,
great. We've achieved actually less
objectification." So, I'm not trying to
suggest that I think that the
overcommodification of women's bodies is
positive. But what I am saying is that
when you're going to the 1950s that we
shouldn't put this glazed look of, oh,
it was so happy we had single-income
households and we got to stay home. We
also had a pill popping problem. We also
were viewed as maids like we were seen
as a house appliance far more than we
were as people. And so when you have
that kind of objectification where you
are in a subservient position,
I think we're facing a different form
today. But I think that rape is a
signifier of a contradiction to your
statement. Okay. Does that make sense?
Um it doesn't make sense, but I I I do
want to rebut it on a couple of points.
First, I just want to say suggesting
that objectification is has gone
downward since the 1950s is well, that's
just a firm no. That is not the truth.
And you know that's not true. Wait, so
do you feel Hold on. Let me let me
answer your second thing. Second thing
you you then brought up, okay, women
were at home, but they were pill
popping. Well, it's you then have to
acknowledge we're actually popping more
pills now, right? So, we have actually
increased our amount of pill popping.
Women are having overdoses on opioids.
And on top of that, since I think 1999,
by rate, we are increasing our opioid
use compared to men. So women are not
popping pills less because we're going
into the workforce. That's actually not
true at all either. We're so we're and
we're also, like I said to you,
consuming alcohol more and binge
drinking more than we did in the 1950s,
which is why I was trying to get her to
say, "We need to look at actually a
reasonable, give me any reasonable
metric of how we can define happiness."
Because it's hard, right? Are you happy?
Yes or no? Sure. But you're Wait, hold
on. We're actually avoiding what my
original point was was about rape being
the signifier. Okay, pause. You've been
voted out by the majority. Please return
to your seat. Thank you. Nice to meet
you.
[Applause]
Hi. Hi. I like your hat. Whitney
Shanahan. Nice to meet you.
I am fascinated by your claim uh that
women have lost happiness since the
sexual revolution since the 1950s. Do
you think that there is any tie to
happiness and freedom and happiness and
choice? Because since 1950s,
since the sexual revolution, women have
gotten exponentially more freedom and
more choice. And for me as a mother and
as a woman, having the freedom to choose
what I do, to make my own destiny makes
me infinitely more happy than say back
before the sexual revolution when I
couldn't get a bank account, couldn't
get a home loan, uh couldn't work
outside the home, couldn't travel around
without a man, uh couldn't control my
own reproduction. So I feel that
happiness, personally, my belief is tied
to our ability to have freedom. And I
think that in the United States,
protecting freedom and our individual
freedoms is what's going to lead us to
happiness. Um, did you go to college?
Absolutely. Okay, great. Did you? Yes, I
did. So, you have a degree? Absolutely.
Now, when you went to college, did you
go to college because it was simply
something that you wanted to do or did
you think that I have to go to college
because in order to get a job, I have to
have a college degree? I went to college
for art because I was fascinated with
art. Okay. Just answering my question,
did you go to co like did was that the
only reason you went to college or did
you think that I might want to do
something in art so I have to go to
college like for my career? I went to
school because I wanted to expand my
horizons. I mean I think that's why most
people go to university. Why? That's
actually that's actually not true. A lot
of I I went and I think a lot of people
go because there's a a pressure that if
you don't go to college, you're going to
be a failure. It's a choice.
Everything's a choice. So taking away
choices doesn't make people happier.
I'm actually I'm disagreeing with you on
the idea that people are feeling more
free by financial pressure. I think
financial pressure makes people feel
remarkably less free. So you want no
bank accounts again. Women not to have
credit cards. I'm not saying that women
shouldn't have access to credit cards or
bank accounts. You're putting words in
my mouth. So why don't you respond to
the words that I'm saying? Well, less
financial pressure. If I don't have a
bank account, that's a lot less
financial pressure. I guess that
financial pressure in terms of most
people that go to college, and I'm I'm
counting myself among them. It's because
typically in order to get the job that
you're being sold is going to make you
infinitely happier and infinitely more
free. It just requires a college degree.
And most of these people, to be clear,
have to put themselves, the majority of
people have to put themselves into debt.
And I don't think anybody would describe
debt as a form of freedom, right? I
don't think anybody would realistically
say, let's get back to happiness. So,
we're here to talk about happiness and
how the sexual revolution and we're not
talking about college debt. I think it's
important because we are we're talking
about freedom. You just said that the
reason why I feel happy is because I
have more freedom. And I am saying that
financial restraints and debt doesn't
make people feel more free. Let's
eliminate the debt. Let's eliminate
college. Maybe we should have a free
college here in the US. That sounds
great. Great idea, Candace. I love that
idea. Love it. Champion. Champion for
the people.
Very nice. All right. Return to your
seat. Surrounded is now a podcast
available wherever you listen. Search
surrounded, plug in, and stay part of
the conversation anywhere, anytime.
[Music]
My second claim is that no career will
give women as much joy and fulfillment
as raising children.
Not today.
Hi, Candace. How are you? Hi. Nice to
meet you. Nice to meet you. I'm John.
Um, okay. So, I feel like a lot of your
arguments today are very rooted in a
sort of
old school perspective. I have to be
honest. Like, I think, and I'm not
trying to be insulting whatsoever, I
feel as though most people would
identify that claim as pretty extreme
and pretty like children are extreme.
Well, no, that that women would get more
happiness inherently from raising kids
than having a job or deciding what they
want to do with their lives. Why is
that? I'm I'm just curious. Why would
having children, which is just a natural
biological conclusion, be something that
sounds extremely I just said inherently.
Inherently, that's the expectation that
that's better for and it's inherent
because it's biological. So, I think
when we think about things that are
inherent, I think biology is a good
thing to start with, right? So,
biologically speaking, men and women
come together, they form families, and
that's the reason why you're sitting
here, that's the reason that I'm sitting
here is because biology is inherent. So
I was saying it's just it's just natural
order that we're speaking about, right?
Okay, let's break it down. So why do why
do you believe that? Why do you believe
that? Why do I believe that? Why do
inherently inherently are happier? Yeah.
Okay. You keep stressing this word
inherent. Yeah. I think because it
speaks to natural order and every piece
of life I think is enriched by children.
You don't think it's natural for women
to get to decide what they want to do
with their lives? I do not think that
saying women can decide whether or not
they want to go to work or have children
is problematic. What I'm saying to you
is that women will get the most
fulfillment from having a family because
it's natural. It's natural, but also
children are wonderful and beautiful and
spiritually divine creatures. I mean,
they're just they're amazing. There's
everything about having a child. It Yes,
it's a lot of work is just it's
beautiful. I hear that. Well, okay. What
if what if there's a a little girl born
and it's her dream her entire life to be
an author or to be you know on TV or any
of these things and having children is
very expensive. It takes a lot of time.
So how is it better for that like and I
understand this is hypothetical but that
hypothetical little girl uh to have
children than to pursue these things
that would make her happy as she gets I
just think that what if she publishes
the book and she has a child she would
agree with me that the child was more
fulfilling and made her happy. That's
what I'm happier than the book did is
what I'm saying. And I say this as a
published author of a New York Times. I
I would choose my children over my
best-selling book. And I was that little
girl who had a dream that like, oh, it
would be really great if I could share
my thoughts and ideas in a book. But it
is utteranity for me to reflect on that
and say that I would have rather
published Blackout than to have my three
children. But why is it rather? You see
what I'm saying? It's it's it's not
rather. I'm just saying that's your
claim is that it's better. will be more
fulfilled. Yes. So rather well if it's
an either or if you're saying it's an
either or I'm just saying that if these
two things are happening have happened
in your life the thing that will bring
you more spiritual fulfillment will be
children. And so women who are
neglecting that who are neglecting the
pathway to you know strive toward family
because they think their career is going
to hug them at night or they think that
when they're on their deathbed their
career is going to come up next to them
and say you were so great to me. I think
that they have stepped into a delusion
and I'm hopeful that they wake up from
it before it's too late. All right,
pause. Sorry, you've been voted out by
the majority. Please return to your
seat.
Hi, nice to meet you. Okay, so currently
women make up about 47% of the
workforce. If this were the case and
that women were just inherently unhappy
or unfulfilled working and would just
prefer to be at home, why don't they?
Because it's we've made that due to
prior feminist waves nearly impossible
because now which I believe that the
reason that the government wanted women
to enter the workforce was because it
gave them an opportunity to tax a
household twice. And so this goes back
to what I was saying is that there's a
lot of financial pressure that is being
exerted on young women to enter the
workforce. And they do so blindly under
this illusion that somehow entering the
workforce is going to make you more
fulfilled. Like getting yourself into
six figures of debt, going to college to
then take on a career and be in debt and
having to pay student loans while you
make 35k is going to make you happier.
And I'm saying that isn't actually true.
Okay. So I hear that. Yeah. At the same
time, would you not agree that men and
that women can both have a career and
have children? I mean, you are actively
doing that right now. And I want to be
very clear because I am actively doing
it right now. I would be someone that
you would call an exception because I
get to work from home. I get to wake up
in the morning. I don't have a boss,
right? I don't have to go into the
office from 9:00 to 5:00. I get to then
therefore spend the entire morning with
my children. So you're an exception. And
the 47% of women that make up our labor
force are also an exception. No, the
exact opposite. So, I'm trying to make
it more realistic because I think it's
it's really bad form when people who are
able to stay at home, right, and are
able to start working at, you know, 1:00
p.m. as I do after being around their
children. The children are running
around all day will then preach to you
that every woman can have this. That's
that's not the reality. The reality is
that the overwhelming majority of people
are stuck behind a desk all day and
they're not happy. They're not doing
work that gratifies them at all. and at
the same time they're suspending. Well,
that's just what career you've chosen.
But I think that the issue still work a
9 to5. I think that's that's okay. Yes.
But if it's the job that is making them
unhappy, then maybe they should have
chosen a different career path and not
the structure of the career itself. But
my issue with this is that not only is
it claiming that women can't both be
mothers and have jobs, which we know to
be true because millions of women do
that. My mother does that. You are
actively doing it right now. But it also
is qualifying what every single woman in
this country wants without any clear
evidence. I mean, there's 169 million
women in this country over. How can you
say that you know exactly what every
woman secretly wants? Are you I didn't
that wasn't my claim that I secretly
know what every single woman wants. I'm
saying that if you measure up at the end
of your life what brought you more
fulfillment your career or a child
raising children in your family we will
discover that and and there there
actually have been studies people have
gone to people on their deathbeds and
the number one regret that people have
was that they gave too much to their
careers and this includes men by the
way. Well, yeah, that's true. I mean, of
course, human relation is going to be
valued over money and profit, but at the
same time, what does that even agree
with my argument? You're agreeing with
my argument. Humans prefer humans over a
job. But that's not just singular to
women. That's everyone. And my question
is, what does that even have to like
what is the goal of that? Should every
woman quit working and just have a
child? Well, I'm just trying to warn you
that if you decide to suspend that
pursuit of family because you think that
you have to first climb the ladder, a
lot of women make that mistake and they
don't end up finding a partner. That's
their right. It's free will. You
definitely have a right to make. You
don't get to say what people should and
shouldn't do. I didn't come I don't
think my claim is this is what people
should or should not do. I'm just simply
stating that my claim is that you will
be more fulfilled if you focus on
trying. You need to decide what other
people are fulfilled by. Okay. I I am
making my claim here that you will women
are infinitely more fulfilled in the
household and raising children than they
are taking that 9 to 5 job. But you have
no evidence of that. In fact, you are
evidence against your own claim. I am
not evidence against my own claim. I'm
saying that you're here at work right
now. I'm literally I've literally said I
am telling you women cannot have it all.
That is an illusion and that is an
illusion that is stressing women out.
And I think it is the reason why so many
women are turning to popping pills. why
there's been such a significant more
than a thousand% increase since men can
have it all. Men can be fathers and have
a job, but women can't do that. I don't
think you can have it all. It sounds
like you're devaluing women. I think
that women can do everything that a man
can do and men have done this
historically throughout time in
memoriam. I think women women is our
topic debate topic today. So, I mean
women exist in a society with men. We
are comparing women are trying to be
both women and men. And that is why
women are unhappy today is because
actually what's quite ironic about the
feminist movement is that I think women
are just trying to be people. I think
women have been taught that being a
woman is not enough and that you have to
also aspire to be a man. And that's the
irony. It's like a psychological
conditioning. What feminists went out
and did and said is that in order for
women to have value, women need to be
like men. And I'm saying that actually
women and men are biologically
different. There are differences in our
behavior. There are differences in our
desires. And I think evidence of the
feminist movement, by the way, shows us
that because even when women enter into
the college education space, the
pathways of career that we choose are
different from men because we're
biologically different, right? Okay. So,
let's say that this is true, that women
truly are more fulfilled at home. Now,
the average cost of raising a child a
year is around $21,000 or more. So my
issue is, are you saying that women
should just suddenly stop working and
now the onus is entirely on men? Like
the society that you're pitching is not
sustainable economically. It was
sustained economically, but it's not
right now. Naima, you've been voted out
by the majority. Please return to your
seat.
Hi. Hi, Cassie. Nice to meet you. Nice
to meet you. Um, so your claim is that
women will be h happier at home. I think
you're conflating though happiness with
importance because I get what you're
saying where a woman can write a book
and have kids but the kids are always
going to make her happier. But I think
it just means that kids are always going
to be more important, not necessarily
make you happier. But also piggy packing
on Naima, we don't live in an economy
where people typically can have a
one-inccome household, right? Whether it
be the mom or dad that stays home. Um,
and so I think and you keep bringing up
the 1950s, which cuz it was right before
the I just don't know if that's the
period of time that you want to go back
to. No, it's just I'm just going back to
the first wave of feminism. You want to
undo progress that's been done. So I'm
curious as to what decade you'd be
comfortable living in, especially as a
black woman. Okay. So we're going to
park aside the race politics because I
want to I want to f focus on Okay. Then
as a woman, what period of time do you
want to go back to? Uh just as a woman,
I think that it was probably a better
environment for women when we were we
understood that raising our children was
fulfilling. But some women still do
understand that, right? And a lot of
women and I'm here advocating for you to
be able to live the life that you want
and for other women to be able to live
the lives they want. Do you have
children? No. Okay. You have a career, I
presume? Yeah. Okay. What What do you
work? What field do you work in? I do
hair. Okay. Wonderful. So I have both
children and a career as somebody
pointed out. And so the fact that I'm
saying that you will be infinitely more
fulfilled at the end of the day by
raising your children than you will be
if you come home and you say, "Wow, I
really crushed it dying somebody's hair
today." What is it exactly that makes
you angry about hearing that? Like
that's what I'm I'm actually trying I'm
trying to get I'm trying to get to the
implicit revolution. The thing is that
no one mentions children. No. See, no
one's angry when you mention children. I
get angry, I guess, when you mention
that someone should have a children or
you're trying to impose a lifestyle onto
people that you want to live, which I
think is kind of funny because as
someone who's anti-feminism, you
practice it more than most women do. I
mean, every time you get on your
podcast, every time you collect a check,
you're practicing feminism. Okay. That's
what you think. No, that's what it is.
Because without feminism, you wouldn't
be able to exist. Yeah. People keep
saying I hate when people say that. just
shows that you you haven't done the
research to even understand where the
feminist or you don't know history which
was discoverable that that's what I'm
saying about you because it means that
you don't understand that a bunch of
government officials in the CIA funded
the feminist movement. So for all of
your hatred for the patriarchus so my
question is is it bad that they funded
it or bad that it just happened? Men
wanted men wanted women to go into the
workforce. The government which had a
lot of men was being Are you talking
about because World War II occurred and
we had to go to factories and then when
we left the factories they forced us
back into the homes. That's not what I'm
saying at all. So let me tell you what
I'm saying and then you can respond to
it.
Gloria Steinum is considered to be a
feminist icon, right? Because she led
these protests. She also had a bunch of
music festivals. She got students
involved. It is just a fact that Gloria
Steinum was funded by the CIA. Okay. The
CIA being the maledominated CIA of the
50s and the 60s funded those movements.
So what what what do you think was the
explicit aim? Do you think it was
because the government really wanted you
to be more free that they wanted to
encourage women to enter? Well, I have
to be honest with you. I couldn't speak
on behalf of the government. You know
what I mean? And what their intention?
Well, I think it's important because you
just said that I don't know history and
I think it's pretty important if you're
going to sit across from me and say I
don't know history that you learn a
piece of history and then question. You
keep bringing up men and I think it's
funny cuz we should talk about men more
like you brought up suicide. They're
four times more likely to kill
themselves which is why and while women
we're twice as more often on
anti-depressants, but that's cuz we go
out and do what we need to do to keep
coping. And we need to focus on men and
the patriarchy because it's actually
oppressed them just as much as women now
emotionally, right? Because when we're
kids, we are our parents teach us how to
cross the street. Look both ways so you
can get the other side unharmed. When a
boy comes across a feeling, and I'm
using men and boys here because they're
the ones suffering. Women are too, but
emotionally. When they come across a
feeling they haven't felt before, we
have to teach them how to get to the
other side and cope with it. Otherwise,
they stay where they are. That anger and
resentment builds. That's the feeling
they become most comfortable with.
That's the feeling they go to first in
most situations. So, we need to stop
telling our boys that they don't cry,
cuz they do. They just do it alone and
then they become even more alone.
All right. Uh, Jasmine, nice to meet
you. Okay, so you say that women are
more fulfilled at home with kids than
going out into the workforce or getting
educated, but that just really doesn't
bear out when you look at the stats.
When you look at how working mothers are
way less likely to be in poverty,
maternal education is the number one
predictor of childhood outcomes, better
scores, uh getting higher incomes in the
future, fewer behavioral problems,
better mental health. So, it's weird to
me with and college educated women are
least likely to get divorced, and
they're the only women the top 10% of
women are the only women whose marriage
rates are going up. So, they're getting
married, they're staying married, and
their kids are doing better. When you
look at stay-at-home mothers, you see
that they're more likely to report being
depressed. they're more likely to report
having um anxiety and anger and all
these types of things. So, how can you
say that? Seems like a woman if you want
to get married and have kids, you should
go to college and have a career. So, I
it sounds to me like we are looking at
totally different statistics because
everything that you said I I've actually
read the exact opposite. I'm glad we're
on a fact check show with you. Exactly.
So exciting. That's going to be amazing.
Okay. Because I know, like I said, I I
think what we're talking about is that
there was this widespread report on
female happiness. And I I know that it
was it was formally debunked and it was
that's not what I'm talking about. Pew
Research, University of California. In
fact, working mothers today spend more
time with their ch children than women
did in the 1960s that were at home.
Okay. Well, women that I can tell you
women that are at home are obviously
spending more time with their children
than the people who are at work. And
their children are not fairing off any
better and they're fairing off worse.
How are you measuring their children
fairing off worse? uh how likely they
are to uh higher incomes, better scores,
fewer health problems, fewer behavioral
issues, and better mental health. So the
the just to get back to the claim that
I'm making here is that it is obvious
that women who have children are going
to be more fulfilled. How is that
obvious? Because you said so.
No, it's not obvious because I said so.
It's because when you look at all the
statistics in terms of women who are
choosing not to have families, they are,
as the person who just sat here before
you mentioned, they are suffering from
more depression. They're suffering from
more anxiety. And I and that's not true.
Okay, it is true. It is actually true
that women who are choosing their
careers overstarting families are
finding themselves leaning more onto on
to medicines like Xanax, anxietyinducing
medicines and depression because they
suspended that time frame where women
really should be looking to find a
partner and to start a family because
they were instead pursuing their
careers. There has been a there it has
been it is a dishonest it is is totally
a dishonest narrative that men and women
want the same things out of life. We
don't we absolutely do not want the same
things out of life. In fact, we don't
even measure we don't even measure
success the same. Men and women don't
even measure success the same. So, but
tell me how the women who are working
and getting educated, why are they
fairing off better in all of these? I am
telling you that I do not believe they
are fairing off better in all these
measures. I do not because because of
what? I am telling you that we are
looking at totally opposite statistics.
Like, so you're sitting here telling me
that the statistics show that women who
are working are producing better
children. But I am saying that women
that grow up in a a two family home
where the mother stays at home are
fairing off better than the the children
who are being raised in an environment
where both of the parents are away from
the home. I do get to work from home.
No, but that's the watch your show. You
talk about all the nannies you hire and
it's so hard to find a talked about all
of the nannies I hire. You have I spoke
about how difficult it was to find a
babysitter who knew how to cook a meal
and that's because you don't need a
babysitter. You're already you could
retire right now. have to let people
respond to you when they're when they're
speaking. You don't want to to respond
to you when it's No, you don't want to.
You want to be working, which is great.
You're telling me what I want now and
then accusing me of telling you. Wait,
are you don't want to work? Can you just
let me finish? Cuz you've said so many
words that you just What you're trying
to do here, like your argument style is
I'm going to say so much, not let her
get a word in, and then walk away and
feel like I've won. We're not having a
conversation because you've not let me
respond to you for one of your points.
Okay. What I am saying to you, first to
answer what you just said, which was a
lie. What I spoke to about on the
weekends is that it's been increasingly
difficult to find a 25-year-old who even
knows how to make box macaroni and
cheese, right? It's and that's crazy.
That's and that is in large part due to
feminism. Women don't even focus. Women
don't even focus. Like there's this
there's this there's this idea that
women shouldn't be cooking. Like there's
something fundamentally wrong with women
even learning how to cook. Spending as
much time with your children as you
possibly can because that's the way to
get the most fulfillment. No. And that's
what I'm trying to say. I am speaking to
you as stop. Okay. Could you please let
somebody get inward edgewise? You're
not. You actually have not let anybody
finish. And like I said, it's it's no
one benefits when you're just speaking
over me and not allowing me to respond.
All you're proving is that you have an
attitude and you believe in feminism,
but you're not see that's what I'm
saying. You just have an attitude and
it's not it's not it's performative.
Address my point. I will be quiet if you
point. Does anybody actually feel here
that I am being allowed to address any
of her points when she just keeps
running over me? Like you I'm literally
trying to answer your first point of you
saying that I don't stay at home. Yeah,
really weird. Fair point. Obviously, I
get that you're all anti-Canis and pro-
feminist, but also it's not productive
if you're not actually Okay, address the
point. You spend more time saying that
I'm not addressing that you you don't
have a chance to talk when you the whole
time. You could have addressed the point
and you could have talked. I go for it.
I just want you to know that you're not
coming across as somebody who wants to
actually have a conversation. So, to get
back to the claim because I don't even
know where you're at. You're now
talking. You're saying, but I said stuff
on my podcast. I'll go wherever you want
to go. I'll go wherever. So, do you want
to start with me working at home?
Because I work at home. You just said
something about me working. You travel
all around the world. Okay. I you you
you're do speeches and I love that. I
love how ambitious you are. That's a
really great trait. And if you were
truly said that you would be more
fulfilled. Now, one thing you do find is
women, they don't want to stay at home
when you pull them. They just want
flexible working hours and flexible
working conditions like you have. And I
think we should all advocate for that.
It's not one or the other. But when you
sit here and you go, you'll be more
fulfilled doing this and spend all your
time doing that. We would love for you
to leave the public eye and go focus on
what makes you fulfilled. Okay.
Hey, before we go any further, we want
to take a moment to say thanks so much
to Straight Arrow News for powering the
fact checks in this video. Straight Air
News is on a mission to raise the bar on
journalism in a time of media bias and
mistrust. Straight Air News helps you
quickly find trusted information you
need to understand the news, allowing
you to dive deep into the topics that
matter to you and the world around you.
Their work is trying to break the bias
bubble, helping you understand how every
side of the political spectrum is
reporting on a story so you get a full
picture of the news. That's why we're so
happy to be partnering with Straight
Arrow News. They deliver the facts
unbiased, balanced, and designed to make
sense of a complex world, getting you
the clarity you deserve and news you can
trust. Go to s.com/surrounded
or click the link in the description to
check it out. By clicking that link,
you're not just supporting this channel,
you also take advantage of a better way
to get the news. Welcome back to
Trustworthy Journalism. Thanks again to
Straight Arrow News for partnering with
us on this episode. Now, let's get into
it. My next claim is that we live under
a matriarchy, not a patriarchy.
Hi. Hello. Nice to meet you. It's a
pleasure to meet you. I'm Princeella the
queen maker. I love that. So, you say we
live in a matriarchy, right? Can you
give me the definition of patriarchy?
Yes. Well, the patriarchy is the idea
that the the the system our system in
America is being run by men and that
women are having to exist under a system
that immediately disadvantages them
because men are behind it. And I
disagree with that pointedly. I think
actually we're living in a society where
people are being very much influenced
socially and politically by women. Okay.
So the denotative definition of
patriarchy is father rule and where
positions of government are held
majority major majorly by men where
women are largely largely excluded. So
125 house of representatives are female
and that's only about 25% right and only
about 28% make up senate and 3.3% of
congress up until this date have ever
been women. So by denotative definition,
we literally live in a patriarchy. Yes.
So I disagree with that. So I think what
this gets to, which is actually an
important part of the conversation, is
that people always think that where
there is disparity, there's somehow
inequality and I actually reject that
entirely. I think it's just a difference
in what we're interested in. I think
we're biologically wired. We're
interested in different careers. And
just because we looked if we looked in
the fashion industry and said, "Oh,
well, it's being dominated by women." It
wouldn't mean that, okay, well, that
means that the fashion industry is a
matriarchy and men have no sense. It
just means have no ability to
communicate how they feel in the fashion
industry. I literally think that those
numbers show that we're just
biologically different. So, I actually
think politically women have shown that
they have a lot more power than men
have. And I'm talking about just in
terms of political movements. The most
recent I can think of is the Me Too
movement, right? If a bunch of women get
together and complain about a man and
refer to the patriarchy and scream,
generally speaking, and let me know if
you agree, the media will celebrate
that. If a bunch of men got together and
were shrieking and speaking about women,
generally speaking, the media would call
them all white supremacists and say that
we had a misogyny problem and that
things were really wrong in society.
Women are allowed to be more vocal in
general about problems than are Well,
let me let me speak to that. When we're
talking about government and media,
these are two different things. So under
the denotative definition of a
patriarchy by the percentages that are
occupied in the government, which is
majority male defines us as a
patriarchy. Now when it comes to for
capitalism, for marketing purposes and
control for capital and revenue, that is
a totally different conversation. But
who's making the laws? I don't think
that women are the ones voting to have
their reproductive rights taken away
where you have rape, incest, and all of
these things excluded to force women to
be able to have I don't think women in
government would largely vote against
their own interests because it's
majority male patriarchy. Okay. I think
love that point. Are women allowed to
vote? Oh, of course they are. Who's
voting those that patriarchy? And then
out of curiosity, no, I totally agree.
And and and you want to know why?
Because there are so many women who
think like you. You submit to the idea
of men ruling everything and your
ideology is spread across a lot of women
who also falsely believe to vote against
their own interests just to complain
about it in the end. You know you
earlier you said that you know women
would be much more happier working uh at
home. But don't you agree that it's
human nature to want things that you
don't have? So during the 1950s, which
is something that you constantly bring
up, you know, it wasn't until 1994 that
it was legally illegal to beat your
wife. And so what we're dealing with is
people wanting something and then when
they get it, they're not happy with it.
And then they have to revoke that idea
for something else. And so what you're
saying is that women vote for these
things because they have the same
mentality as you. Okay. So you're
acknowledging that women have the
freedom to vote. Yes. And you're saying
that women are still existing mentally
even with the freedom to vote. Correct.
They are voting men in because we are
still victims of No, I don't believe in
victimhood. I believe in lack of
education and lack of knowledge. Because
one of the things that you also said,
you think that it could just be that
more men are running for positions of
office? No, not necessarily. Because
remember the United States, the average
reading comprehension of people in the
United States is sixth grade. So we're
not dealing with educated people. Lack
of education is the cause for what we
see in the world. And if we educate the
women better because a nation can rise
no higher than this woman. And if she
reading and comprehending at a sixth
grade level and popping out a lot of
kids, you know, cuz the brokeest people
in the world pop out the most kids. So
if we have those people voting, of
course they're going to vote against
their interest because they voting for
some utopian society that will never
exist. Okay. So that's that's why you
think Camala lost. This ain't even about
Camala. You're talking about women. No,
but we had an opportunity. Yeah. Go
ahead. We had a male running and we had
a female running and it we actually
showed that Trump increased the amount
of women who voted for him. Right. So
I'm I'm asking you, do you believe that
the reason that happened was because
women became less educated during that
time? They've always been less educated.
Do you know that UNESCO says that the
that 2/3 of the 700 the 7.7 million
illiterate adults is women? Illiterate.
And we have sixth grade educated people
voting. And guess who that guess the
dominant population? It's white women.
And so guess what? Now you have to add a
race element into that which you already
know exists because we as black folks we
ain't the dominant people voting people
in. Okay. So now when we have to go into
white supremacy and feminism now you
have to look at the mind of the people
who actually have economic success and
what they're voting for because classism
actually matters as well. So I'm sorry
but a lot of people vote based on their
feelings and not based on policy. Pause
guys. Yes. Sorry. You've been voted out
by the majority. Please return to Thank
you for the respectful conversation.
Hi. Hi. How are you? Great to meet you.
I'm doing well. Nice to meet you. So, I
view this argument as um a matter of
fact, right? This is a descriptive claim
about the uh culture reality we live in
and uh patriarchy being uh a system in
which men hold the predominance of power
in both political economic and social uh
methods of organizations. So S&P 500
companies 90% of CEOs are men board
members 70% of CEOs are men 70% of
congressional members are men. Now, you
may provide some sort of naturalistic
argument to why that is, but what you're
essentially arguing then is that there's
a natural patriarchy, which I think
feminists would all disagree with. We
think that there's um a clear uh social
pressure as to why this is. And part of
the evidence for that is since
feminism's um you know, arise within our
our public culture, we've now seen an
explosion of women entering these
fields, but we have a long way to go.
But fundamentally, the claim regarding
patriarchy or matriarchy, we are so much
closer to where we were just a few
decades ago or several a couple
generations ago where women couldn't
hold a credit card than a system where
men can't hold a credit card. We're
still much closer to that um form of
society. Why would you say that we're
closer to that? What do you mean by
that? Did you just qualify that? Because
in terms of economic power, so for
example, house household wealth, women
own 55 cents to every dollar a man owns.
Who who controls household spending
though? You talk about how the money's
made in America. How is it being spent?
Who's So, it's primarily spent by women
as you've noted, but then the money
where the profit's being generated. It's
being generated by Would you rather be
the people that are spending and
deciding on what the money is being
spent on or would you rather be the
person that's just working to to earn
you? Well, CEOs and board members aren't
working. They're they own the shares and
they're they're making the profit when
you own it. You would you would Yeah.
You would much in a capitalist system by
definition you would much rather be
making the profit than than spending. I
would much rather be spending your money
than having to work for your money. Just
so you're just so we are so totally
clear here. I would much rather spend
your money than have to go out and earn
your money. Well, you're you're talking
about wage laborers in terms of working.
But in terms of No, I'm talking about
spending power, right? Yeah. Well, sure.
But that matters. If 85% of 85 cents of
every dollar how that's being spent is
being determined by women, that's a
that's power that we can't say spending
power is not power. Why why why do you
think that is the case? It's because
women are often relegated to the role of
doing grocery shopping etc. because for
for millennia now uh or from millennia
up until now uh women were unable to
enter the workforce and have economic
political. So, let's get into the
reasons cuz you brought up something
that men are the people that are at the
top of these companies, these these
Fortune 500 companies and political
power. You're absolutely right. Why is
that? It's it's it's primarily because
we the women haven't broken the ceiling
quite yet in terms of uh meeting men in
terms of uh parody with with these sorts
of powers. But what we've seen with the
explosion of feminism is that women have
actually begun to enter uh uh these
companies have uh you know risen into
both political and economic positions of
power. But that continues to grow year
by year which shows that these social
pressures are actually breaking apart as
soon as feminism comes into play. What
shows that women and men have different
interests and I think this gets into
what I was saying that just because you
see a disparity does not mean that it's
not just a disparity in what our
interests are. That's what's being
represented. I don't know why there has
been this idea that women should want to
aspire to work 80 hours a week in order
to be on par with men. Do you think that
interests are innate or do you think
that interests are inate? So why is it
then that for example in the 1980s only
a quarter of college graduates were
women where now majority of college
graduates are women. That shows that
because of the way that social pressures
have actually changed, women's interests
are actually now changing too. a
majority I think or at least half of uh
law school graduates are now women. It
used to be the case in for example a few
hundred years ago that a lot of uh
primary philosophers like Emanuel Kh
Hegel didn't even believe women could uh
be reasonable. Now here you are today
doing a debate with me where we're using
logic and reason to get to these and
nobody here would dismiss the claim that
you can't be rational or logical or be
for example a great lawyer because
you're a woman. Right. So I I totally
agree with you that women but I think
they have actually entered into the
workforce. I mean entered into college
under this external pressure of feeling
that if you don't go to college you're
going to be a failure. So you admit the
pressures are a part of the way
interests. Yes. But we're disagreeing on
where the pressure is coming from. Like
I think that now the pressure is that if
a woman doesn't enter the force it's
there's there's no longer this idea that
okay we're going to come together as a
family whereas there was this reality
that there was this understanding that
you would have a partner. People were
getting married when they were 18 19
years old. our grandparents. Now it's
because of feminism. And I'm saying this
is actually this is the downside of
feminism. Women no longer have that
sense. They think that if you they have
to be pressured to go take out a loan to
go to college and then you have the
pressure to get Well, they have the same
pressures as men because women no longer
rely on it for an income. Pause. You've
been voted out by the majority. Please.
I did like our conversation. Might have
to come back to you.
Hi guys. Hey Coins, I'm Paris. Very nice
to meet you. Nice to meet you. So, can I
explain to you why I believe we live in
a patriarchy and why I believe we live
in a society that's preferential to men.
So, I'm going to use the example of male
violence. There's a lot of places I can
look, but we're going to talk about
that. 81% of women have been sexually
assaulted. One in six have been raped.
One in four women are the victims of
domestic violence. 98% of perpetrators
of rape and sexual assault are men. 95%
of perpetrators of domestic violence are
men. um actually uh in regards to human
trafficking, 70% of human trafficking
victims are women. So we're seeing a
very clear issue of men being violent
towards women. And then when we look at
the way that our government handles
that, one out of three rapes go
reported. And then out of the ones that
go reported, 7% end in jail time. So if
we're looking at that and we're looking
at the fact that our government doesn't
really get that worried about male
violence.
Well, so what I would say is going back
to biological differences, men are
naturally inclined more towards
aggression than women are. So I I am not
shocked by you telling me it's even if
you looked at, like I said, male-on-male
crime, you would see that there are more
instances instances of men killing other
men than there are instances of women
killing other women. And that I think
actually speaks to our biological
differences, which is actually at the
root of everything that I believe about
feminism being a lie is because they're
trying to program people to believe that
men and women are the same. Now, I don't
think that pointing to the fact that men
are more aggressive than women, which is
a point that you and I 1,000% agree on,
whether or not that manifests in the
very wrong way, men harming men, other
men, which I think they do more probably
than there than they are beating women,
men on male-on-male violence, um, that
manifestation doesn't change the fact
that men and women are just biologically
hardwired different. I think it's
actually proof of that. I don't think it
has anything to do with the fact of of
power dynamics in this country because
to the contrary, if you look at prison
rates and talking about how disparities
don't mean anything, the majority of
overwhelming people that are in prison
are male, right? There's a reason for
that. So when it manifests on in a good
way, that male aggression, you know, is
the reason why we have men defending us,
you know, men that are willing to go to
war and die for our nation. So
aggression being an aspect of
masculinity has nothing to do with the
conversation of whether or not feminism
is harming women today. I mean, I agree
with you that women are biologically
different as men are but I don't what I
want you to connect it to is I guess
power because what I'm talking about
when I say that we're existing under a
matriarchy is that I believe that the
social pressures politically and
socially that are coming and even within
our music if we talk about Hollywood
it's very much has become nothing like
just because like who was on the top
music charts or whatever are women okay
how many women have paid maternity leave
that's not like how how are how are
things panning out in the family courts
Why are abusive men having access to
their children? Like, why are women
making less than men? Like, what I mean,
none of that means anything to me. So,
that gap, obviously, I'm sure you've
recognized the gender gap has been
debunked so many times, it's almost
foolish to debunk it again. Well, you
could say, yeah, that most women will go
into jobs where they're making less. But
then it does answer the question of why
do we not value women's labor? It's it's
not that's not valuing women's labor.
just a reality that if you are going to
be a person that aspires to become a
brain surgeon, you are going to make
more money than a person that aspires to
do something that's you know like in the
household. Can we go back to the
billions question? Yes. Why does our
country not persecute men then who are
rapists? Well, the majority of people
who are in prison are men. So they I I I
don't know what you mean that we don't
prosecute men that are rapists. We even
prosecute people 7% go to jail. Only 7%
go to jail. I don't know what that has
to do with the question of whether or
not we're living in a matriarchy or
patriarchy. Are there preferential to
men? You're saying that they only like
to arrest men when they kill someone,
but they they are our government is is
awarding men for raping women. I don't
understand what you're not They don't
care. Rape is effectively legal. You can
literally rape a woman and you have a
very low likelihood of actually going to
jail as a man. Rape is effectively
legal. It's effectively legal. How many
men are actually going to jail? I will I
actually agree with you that in terms of
sex crimes and I don't know how you're
peeling out women because I would even
and again this is nothing to do with our
argument today but I would even say that
people are not being prosecuted hard
enough when we're dealing with crimes
against children period like talking
about sexual crimes not being prosecuted
in this country is a whole another
conversation and you will not get a
disagreement with me but I think that
it's wrong to say that it's somehow
attached to being a woman when you know
there are so many children that are
going through the exact same thing. I
mean, the light sentences that are
tossed out for pedophiles. It's
completely ridiculous. Terrible, but I
don't think it has anything to do with
conversation that we're having right
now. But I agree with that. Has
everything to do with it, and you're
separating it to make time. You can turn
to your seat. I'm going to add five more
minutes to this claim.
[Music]
Nice to meet you. Hi, Adam. Nice to meet
you. So, your claim is, just to be
clear, that we live in a matriarchy,
right? So I think even you'd agree that
on a global level that's obviously
ridiculous when there are countries
where people literally are honor killed
for like Instagram posts. But even if
we're talking about just the US, right,
we don't have paid maternity leave.
Abortion is illegal in over a dozen
different states. And as someone earlier
was mentioning, women are overwhelmingly
the victims of sexual violence and
domestic abuse. So that doesn't seem
like a very well-designed matriarchy
where women are victims or, you know,
lacking power in so many different
realms of society on like a structural
level. I just do not think that women
are lacking power on a structural level
because they can't which they can by the
way abort their children. Is that like
one of your components is that there's
many states where abortion is illegal.
Do you dispute that? Uh I am going to
dispute that having a child is somehow
something that restricts women in any
capacity like you're saying what about
the ability to decide what you do with
your own body. I don't believe that it's
I don't believe that murder is something
that you should be allowed to and murder
is the legal is actually what you're
doing to somebody else's body. So I'm
pro-life. So that so the the argument
that well women will only be free if
they're able to you know kill off their
own offspring to me is a really
extremely offcolored um yeah well I
guess if you frame it that way everyone
kind of has to agree with you but when
we're talking about abortion when 99%
take place in the first few weeks when
you know there's no phalamus there's no
cortex there's no capacity for
consciousness in the fetus that's
developing saying that that fetus that
has no capacity to be conscious aware
anything else should have the same
rights same bodily autonomy as a And
that is an obvious I mean you're you're
making my point for me that they're
actually making a point that people who
are you know are born with tremendous
disabilities should just be killed
because of cognitive functions and
ability. I don't remember saying that.
When did I say that? The best argument
which again this this is sidetracked.
Let's get back on track. Kill people
with disabilities. Well, I'm saying that
if you're saying no I am saying that if
you're saying that it's cognitive
ability and at what stage ability to be
conscious and just just so we're clear
disabled people are conscious. They're
they're aware. Okay. Um, so the best
argument that it is a life is the fact
that you have to kill it. You have to
have a procedure to kill it, right? So
you have to intervene on the develop
a developing life. If you have to go
into your body and murder it, then I'm
disputing that there's living human
cells in a again. So we could we can
just tack that off because we just have
a fundamental disagreement on what we
can talk about paid maternity leave.
People have been talking a lot about
whether you have to be a mother, you
have to work. A lot of women have to
pick one or the other because in many
cases if you want to have a child first
of all there's a big gap in your resume
so getting a job after that might be
super difficult and then secondly even
in the process of having that child
being pregnant especially in the third
trimester and then raising the child
where the you know the vast majority of
the burden typically is on the mother uh
the the workplace and our system of our
economy is not tailored to make that
easy for them. I actually totally agree
with you and this is this gets into this
I don't no actually I'm agreeing with
you that this pressure that you're
describing exists for women and I'm
saying that it exists for women because
of the feminists that came before who
argued for women to enter the workplace.
So what you're saying is the solution
didn't work and it actually produced
more problems and now we have more
problems and we need more governance to
be able to tackle these problems. So
you're a system that's forcing women to
make certain decisions. I just wouldn't
call that feminist women should have the
option to choose do I want to be a stay
at home mom do I want to work do I have
some mix of both that's the entire point
here but you are also making an argument
that if you are a woman who does run a
business and does have employees that
they should be forced to pay them
maternity leave uh sure yeah okay so
under let me that's like saying taxes
are forced there's certain things the
government does to regulate our economy
to ensure equality and justice and
better outcomes okay but just so you
know when you do that like to a small
business owner developed country does
what you what you are arguing for is
supporting big corporations and taking
out the little guys because I'm arguing
for supporting people that want to be
mothers and also work at the same time.
the mechanism we do that with that can
be subsidies taxes. You can't just keep
you can't say that we can't have the
economic we can't get down to the
economics of what it actually implies
right I have an economics degree and I
can tell you if there's a small business
that can't afford to pay maternity leave
probably subsidize them and help cover
the cost where is the government getting
money from this is like this is tax
revenue I mean right exactly so from us
so from us just to be clear from us and
this is the thing that that gets me
about all of these debates the magic
solution that everybody has is that well
we just need to tax the government every
other developed country has paid But
it's not magic as in like the money is
coming. The money is coming from you.
It's coming from us. So you're you're
sitting here. That's how taxes work. We
should be raising taxes. Okay. And this
is the entire this is the entire problem
is that the government is already taxing
homes times two. And people are already
struggling with what's being taken out
of their taxes. Taxing capital gains
properly or corporate profits properly.
That there's a reason that we should be
taxing more here there.
Don't you guys want like government
officials maybe bring in more revenue to
help women be mothers? Uh what I'm
saying is that you are just creating a
cyclical argument. You're basically
saying that women want to be able to
have it all. Women cannot have it all
because the government the choice to do
what they'd like. Okay. But you're
saying women should be have the choice
to have it all. Okay. So you're saying
that's a really interesting way of
putting like what you're do you have it
all right now where you're working and
you're also a mother. Is that having it
all? I I'm saying that it's not possible
for women to have it all. It is
impossible. And that's one of the
whatever that is is what I would want
other women to have as well, which is
the flexibility to work a job and also
raise kids if they'd like. No, but that
but that's exactly you guys keep arguing
that what people want is more
flexibility. So you're acknowledging
that right now under with feminism on
fire. We are agreeing women in are going
into the workforce. Like I'm I'm just
kind of using a hyperbolic expression
like feminism is everywhere. We are
arguing that women need to have more
opportunities. Women need to have more
rights. They've taken that. Now you have
the majority of people that are
graduating with college degrees are in
fact women. Uh men are committing
suicide at a higher rate than women.
We're looking around the world. Feminism
also would push for like increased
awareness of men's mental health.
That's fine. Great. You love feminism.
That's great. We already know that we
most most Americans agree with me by the
way. Women should have paid maternity.
If you go issue by issue and by values,
they might not associate with the term
feminism because people like you have
made it toxic. But the actual values
under feminism will move the goal and
then when they begin taxing so that we
can account for paid maternity leave for
3 months, which basically means a small
business owner has to not have an
employee while having to pay months and
months and months. Like the person's not
there. They're not actually small
businesses and have the revenue to cover
paid maternity leave. The government
would probably subsidize them to make up
the cost. No, I actually think that the
way things were made more sense where
you had an environment where you could
afford to take care of children with
just one person bringing in income in
the house. Is that possible in the
current environment? OB you can
obviously and things are going to get
way more expensive with these tariffs as
well. Like it's not going to be easy to
afford anything in the coming years. Is
it going to happen overnight? No. But I
think we need to be realistic about the
fact that the first thing didn't work
right. The entire argument, the first
thing was women entering the workforce
is going to make everybody happier and
richer. That was the idea is that women
having the choice to enter the workforce
is better than them being forced to not
do that. That's the argument. Okay, that
actually is not the argument at all. The
argument was that women would become and
I'm talking about what the feminists got
ahead of and this is why like this
imaginary Twitter feminist, but like
right now you're talking to me and
that's not the argument. I'm not
actually debating an imaginary Twitter
feminist. I'm speaking to you and I have
no idea why you're you're becoming
increasingly more rude when I'm just
rebutting your point that you're making.
responding to my point. I am responding
to your point. I'm saying that you're
creating a cyclical argument where you
keep saying that the thing that you just
did that you said was going to be
enough. What we actually need is for
women to just enter the workforce. Oh,
women are in the workforce and actually
not enough. I'm saying we don't have
enough because we don't have enough. And
I'm telling you that you're also not
going to have enough because you're
going to then get be complaining when
you get that paid maternity leave
because you're Okay. Well, they are
arguing for family paid leave. So that's
even better. Yeah. Okay. So you you
might get Do you think fathers should
also be around to help raise children?
Think who's going to work if everybody
goes home every time a child is born.
Everyone's going to have a kid at the
same time. Yes. Pause. All right.
Everyone will have a male partner.
Nice talking to you as well. My final
claim is that feminism has made things
easier for men.
[Music]
Hi. Hi. I'm Jenny. Nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you. You said that feminism
is easier for men or is It's made
things, I think, easier in society for
men. Yeah. Now men don't have to commit
and they're being offered sex from women
for free. So they they have to actually
effectively do less um and be motivated
less because feminism has kind of
insisted on this culture of sex and
hooking up. And I think that that's has
been a net negative for women. On good
faith, I just want to say I think you're
approaching this with like the best
interest for women. Like you think that
is negative for women and harmful. And I
think in some aspects we can agree to
that. Um, I do think that there are some
aspects of sex work or only fans or
whatnot that maybe men are definitely
the huge consumers of, but if we are so
concerned with women putting that out
for free, um, it's not, it's charged,
right? They're making money off of it.
Then why are we not putting the onus
more on men for being the one that is in
control of that demand, right? So we can
take away the supply or, you know,
condemn it all we want, but if there's
no onus on men to be the consumers of
said products, then wouldn't you think
that would solve the issue that you're
bringing up? Yeah, I actually agree with
you on that and and I really get to
that. I want to be very clear when I say
that I'm anti-feminist. This does not
mean that I do not also criticize men. I
think that's something that people get
very wrong. Okay. 1,000% agree. I
believe the problem was seated by the
feminist movement. I think the sex
revolution and telling women, I mean,
literally these people were protesting.
They didn't have their shirts on and
this used to be just your grandparents
couldn't even imagine this, like women
walking down the street and having their
boobs out and their butts out and
Instagram. Um, and it created an
environment where men then had to work
harder uh for a woman's affection, for a
woman to take her clothes off, sex
education in the classroom. There's this
huge myth that people were just doing it
like, you know, oh, we might as well
teach them because the children are just
doing it. Actually, before they
introduced sex education, the majority
of high school graduates were graduating
with their virginity intact. And then
within 10 years of sex education, we saw
a reversal. So, I'm saying feminist
feminism actually seated the problem.
And now the problem is bad. And it's
it's also bad for men. It's it's harmful
for men to be constantly exposed to
pornography and soft pornography. And I
think it actually um in many ways
emasculates men. Okay. But I would say
they are the main social benefactors of
that culture because well first and
foremost as we're talking about women
who have to kind of pick one or the
other or try to manage both and can we
have it all? Like no you can't have it
all. On a day where I really feel like I
gave a little bit more to my career I
ache because I'm I go okay but like now
I feel like I gave didn't give the same
amount to my children. Um and it's a
constant push and pull and it never
feels enough. It really doesn't feel
enough. So like to a degree I think that
feminism does benefit men. I think that
it allows men to be more emotionally
intelligent. It allows them to
understand what that looks like and also
be able to connect with other people,
right? But at the same time, there's so
much work that feminism has done for
women that to say that it benefits men
more, I don't think is an accurate
statement. For example, Title 9 has made
it very possible for women to go to
college 600% more so, right? And I think
that that is a huge benefit that we can
credit to the feminist movement. Though
I understand your point though of trying
to say that like sex work is harmful for
women and more beneficial for men
because they're benefiting from it the
most. But at the same time if you think
they're also suffering from it does that
not contradict your point? Yeah. So I
disagree on the fact that and and we do
agree that more women are going to
college more actually more women than
men are graduating with college degrees
and despite that people are saying that
we still live under a patriarchy. Women
are free to start their own companies.
Women are free to pay women whatever
they want to pay. Women could hire and
in some cases do hire all women. And so
I don't I don't really understand, which
wasn't your argument to be fair, the
idea that even with all of that freedom,
women are still not able to achieve what
men are able to achieve. I think college
education actually has increased women's
stress. And I'm talking about in terms
of how expensive it is. And I know
you're going to then say, well, the
solution to that is we have to then move
the goalpost. And I'm I'm guessing here
you but like college should be free.
Everything should be free. He thinks no.
We just need more free stuff and
obviously nothing's free. We're talking
we're just going to tax.
I just want to say I think the the issue
that we keep coming back to is that you
believe that women would be happiest in
the home where they don't have to work.
And I think most people in general
probably wouldn't like want to work
anyways. But I think the main issue that
we keep avoiding is that this is not an
issue created by feminism. This is an
issue created by capitalism. Yeah. So
I've heard this argument that it's an
issue created by capitalism. But you
don't agree. You think feminism is the
greater issue than the system that the
spend more money to live. Well, we have
to spend more money to live. I I think
in large part because feminists got
duped by the government. And I think
we're we just keep further enslaving
ourselves to the government. I I'm not a
person who believes in big government.
And yet we find that feminists are
constantly like, well, we can deal with
the college issue. we just need more
government. We can deal with the, you
know, needing to have more benefits. We
just need more government. So, it's
like, okay, let's just tax every
household 100%. And I'm trying to
prevent that. And I'm saying that there
was a time in America. And what's
aspirational for me is I was uh, you
know, raised in part by my grandparents.
They were very happy. They were just I I
lived in that environment of what that
looked like. And I think, okay, for many
of people who didn't grow up there,
feminism has taught us, and I say this
as someone who had to take feminism 101
courses when I was in college, that it's
it was like this nightmare and people
weren't happy and people were suffering
and women were just suffering. People,
you know, were being forced and that
there weren't actually these things that
just marriages that worked, that the
women actually weren't disempowered by
being the CEOs of their household. Well,
allowing women to have more choice and
freedom and agency to leave. Sorry,
you've been voted out by the majority. I
did enjoy this conversation being very
respectful.
I was thinking that a lot of your claims
are very contradictory, saying that we
live in a matriarchy, that men benefit
from feminism more.
I would like to understand why again you
think that men benefit from feminism
more. Um, basically because men don't
have to commit to women. men are still
able to do what they're doing and they
have they are allowed to basically step
away from all of the responsibilities of
what it really meant to be a man and
lead a household. Uh and that's in large
part I think due to the sexual
revolution.
I mean is it really bad that we don't
have to give men the chase? Is it don't
they have gratification from chasing us?
Like it's a hunter versus prey situation
to me. So, I feel like a lot of
relationships, especially back then,
were based on trying to get to home run
like very fast. And now that we have the
freedom to not commit and not tie
ourselves to one man for the whole the
rest of our life, um, I just don't
necessarily think that's bad. I just
don't think the revolution has decreased
our value. We're not chewed gum. We're
people who value connection. And sex
doesn't always have to have this deep
meaning. It is just connection and
intimacy between two people who trust
each other. And why do we have to deny
women that gratification like men you
say are wired to want that? Why not
women? Why? Uh well, we have we again I
go back to just our basic biological
differences. There was a really
interesting book that was done by a
biophysicist. He I think recently passed
away named Edward O. Wilson where he
just sort of breaks down the biological
arguments. Basically, he looks in the
wild to see the behavior of animals. His
thesis is just that you can never you
basically can never beat your own
biology. And then he kind of compares it
to what we see here as just humans and
our social interactions and things that
have been abundantly clear. When you
look at every civilization over time,
whether it's from, you know, 400 BC to
LA today, what are these habits that you
can see that never go away? And people
coming together and starting families is
one of these things because we are
biologically wired to find a family, to
settle down, and to have children. And I
think when you have women that are going
out and they're giving all of the goods
up for free, the goods, the goods, the
goods. I'm not going to say I'm not
going to the goods up for free. Men are
not all of the goods for free from men
and that we are very actually very
certainly do that. And there's
connections. We're not saiy salmon.
We're not made to breed and have
families and then die. You are welcome
to do that. I'm just saying that when it
comes time for you to find a partner,
you may find yourself in a circumstance
where men don't value you as high
because men men like, like you spoke to,
men like to compete. They like to feel
like they've won something. I'd like to
deprive men because they don't need to
have that. That's actually like that's
actually But you did bring up you did
bring up Yeah. And that's what you say
that men are, you know, essentially
predatory and we have the goods that we
have to like keep from them. Oh, I
didn't mean the goods in a bad way. Um,
that's such an objectifying way. the
goods what the grocery goods honestly I
I think I think that that's just kind of
it we don't have value
songs today I think we have value apart
from how many people we sleep with how
many like you also devalue education for
women and I think that's very
interesting because you're also a very
educated woman and in a lot of ways this
is just like an observation you you
devalue yourself a lot I definitely do
not feel like I'm devaluing myself um
make him a sandwich Yeah.
Yes. Which is the title of my book. Yes.
Feed your men and everything. Feed the
people that you love because family
isn't defined just by your partner or
your kids. Family is community and you
should care about your community and
understanding that I just don't think
you really care about the community that
much when you're pushing this rhetoric
of devaluing women so much to stay in
the kitchen, stay within the homes, and
also saying that they're wasting money
on college when education is very
important. There's a lot of female
scientists. Applause. You've been voted
out. Sorry. Sorry. You've been voted
out.
Thank you. Hello. Hi. How are you?
What's your name? I'm Zolola Stone. Very
nice to meet you, Zia. You have very
pretty eyes. Thank you. Um, so you keep
talking about Only Fans and Kim
Kardashian and um, well, I do Only Fans.
Okay. And I'm a stripper as well. So
you're in the sex industry. Um, well,
I'm mainly a recording artist, but I do
that to fund the music. Okay. But, you
know, you're saying basically that we
kind of like devalue ourselves, but at
the same time, I'm celibate. I still
consider myself a woman of God. And so,
you know, not all of us are just out
there just, oh, hey, showing the goods,
you know, like we do respect our bodies
still. So, I don't like that you kind of
putting us all in one box because of
that. So, we have to in order to have
debates, we have to make
generalizations. Of course, there can be
some exceptions to the rule, but what
I'm trying to understand is how can you
say that you're not, you know, giving up
your body if you are a stripper? Well,
cuz I said I'm celibate. I still want to
get married. I still want to have kids.
And for some of us, it's hard for us to
have kids. And I've also dealt with
sexual abuse since a child, you know.
So, I wasn't doing any sexual work as a
child, you know, and still went through
things like that. So, so I first want to
say perfectly sympathetic to everything
you're saying, especially if you come
from an environment where you've lived
through something when you're a kid. It
makes it infinitely harder. And it's
actually a reason why so many people
turn to sex work because they don't have
that structure um at home that gives
them I think other options. But would
you agree with me that if you could like
that wouldn't I went to college for
music production? For music production.
I went to LA recording school. Okay. So
did you decide to be a stripper because
of economic restraint or because of
freedom?
For freedom. You know we want the choice
to do whatever we want with our bodies.
Okay. you know, um I don't think it
matters. If you do want to dress how you
want to dress, that doesn't mean, oh,
you can, you know, sexually abuse or
sexually harass. Okay. Do you think the
men that are being brought into the
strip clubs to watch you? Do you think
that they're walking away and going, I
did that because that woman was
empowered to take off her clothes, or do
you think that they're actually
devaluing women? No, I get it. I used to
be that hypocrite, you know? I said
things that I said I would never do
anything like that, you know? Like I
totally get that, but some people just
want to go to the club and have a good
time. Yeah. I think most of the people
who are making those decisions are doing
it because they have they're dealing
with addictions themselves. I think
you're worth more than taking your
clothes off. I think that if you wanted
to have a career in music, you wouldn't
have to take your clothes off to do
that. And I think that it's sad that
you've been Every story is different.
Every story is different. But I do think
that, you know, we can make a
generalization. I was at that point
where I was going to college. I was
working three jobs. I used to be a
nurse. So, you just don't know the
situations. You don't know how life is
going to turn out. It's going to be ups
and downs. But, no, I didn't want to do
it. But in my situation and things that
I went through, it's something that it
just But I'm actually really glad that
you said no, I didn't want to do it and
you were put in a situation where you
had to do it because I think that's
really honest. And I think the problem
that I find with feminism is that it's
it's tremendously it's a dishonest
movement. All right, guys. Pause. Been
voted out by the majority. Thank you.
I'm not judging.
Nice to meet you. I'm Nice to meet you,
Catherine. Candace, you brought up a
book about that we are going to biology
and that biology is what we should
organize society on based on like what
skills men are good at. I can I can
restate what I said there that there is
a book and the argument that's being
made is that you can't override you
can't outthink your biology is the
easiest way to say it. So feminism I
would say is a movement where they are
trying to outthink biology meaning that
all we have to do is this this this and
that and then magically we're going to
be transformed and that desire within us
to want to start a family is just going
to like die or we're going to be happier
doing this thing and I think the answer
to that is no, right? Mhm. Um, I would
argue that our biology does not have as
much of an effect on the things that we
choose to do with our careers, with our
life choices as you think it does. Our
closest ancestors are chimps and
bonobos. Bonobos are matriarchal. Chimps
are patriarchal. So, and our previous
societies have run egalitarian for
millennia. It's not been this inherent
desire for men to rule a certain way and
women to rule another way. It has been
egalitarian. It's been matriarchal. It's
been patriarchal because there are
things that go into
effect like your situation, your
personality that make you better at
doing something than just your biology.
I know many quiet nerdy men that would
not be good leaders and I know many
strong women and vice versa. Like it
does not matter as based your
testosterone, the hormones you admit is
not going to have as much of an effect
as I think you think it does. I totally
think it does. And so that's why let's
getting back to college since I'm I'm
assuming you support women going to
college. Can you explain why there is
when they can freely choose why there is
such a difference in the majors that
women choose versus the majors that men
choose when they get to college? Well, I
think it's also important to note that
things are changing and there's like
many initiatives to get more women into
STEM, to get women into higher paying
career fields. When women have been kept
out of these fields for so long, it's a
slow and steady race to get them there.
It's not that women are not choosing
them. It's they're slowly learning that
this is okay for them to choose. There's
more women in STEM. There's more
lawyers. There's more women women are
making up strides to those positions.
So, it's not like they're sedentary and
they're staying in these humanities or
arts fields. I don't think you're being
honest. I think you know like if did you
go to college? I mean I'm in college. I
think I know that I mean aren't it's not
because they're not pressured. It's
because when quite literally they say,
"What are you interested in?" Women
flock to certain things. They just do.
We do. We as a whole do. It tends to be
and this is because we are biologically
wired. And even when a child is born,
when a a woman like a a female uh a
child versus a male child, the girls
start speaking faster and they speak
more words. Just a fact, right? For the
rest of their lives. Like my daughter
started speaking and this is not
anecdotal, but this is I'm giving you an
anecdotal example of something that is a
real fact. So there's just a biological
proclivity there that women like
communication and you see that followed
all the way as an example into college.
Women are drawn towards these careers
that are compassionate, emotional and
communicative which is why you'll see
women flooding journalism. That's why
even when you see women that are finding
success, they are typically in careers
that are communicative and
compassionate. Women that will say I
want to do psychology. I want to do
children's psychology. And so even at
the same time that women are saying that
they're running away from their biology,
so to speak, they are still exhibiting
that they very much believe in these
determined biological characteristics
that I think are something that's just
never going to go away. Right. But I
would also bring up that the the way
that women are young girls are given
dolls, young boys are put in sports.
These things that kids learn at a very
early age are very impactful in what
children like and pursue in the future.
It's not simply that I don't think
there's a biological gene that women
like fashion and men don't. That's why
we do see men in fashion. That's why
there's actually at the top of all these
fashion houses a lot of men are in
successful positions in fashion. Um the
way in which you teach a children to
explore creativity and to play in what
we put women in. You put women in pink
rooms and little girls in pink rooms and
boys in blue room. That has an effect.
So, and I'll tell you why I disagree.
And I know because I had my children
back to back that there was there
there's a blur here. So, I never had to
separate them and say, "You play with
this, you play with that." They were
growing up with their toys. I mean, one
year apart, my daughter and my son, they
just are interested in different things.
And this is one of the I think lies of
feminism. And when you actually have
children, there may be some exceptional
child, but I am telling you, my boy's
first word was car. He is obsessed with
trucks. He's obsessed with cars. I did
not do that. I do not like I don't like
having to answer his questions about
cars. I don't like having to answer his
questions about trucks because my
biological proclivities are not designed
I I'm just not feeling passionate about
engineering and wanting to know how
everything works. You don't recognize
that and this is I think one of the
worst harms of feminism because I was a
feminist when I was in college or I I at
least thought I agreed with the movement
because you don't have the family yet.
So when they make these arguments that
you're making, you think that that's
real. You think, "Oh, well, it's just
because you're not giving the child the
the Barbie doll that they don't love
Barbie dolls." And that's not a reality.
We are just quite literally different.
There are many. I'm sorry. I'm so sorry.
Time is up.
I am going to choose Jenny to have a
further conversation with because I
thought that it was a respectful
dialogue and I want people to be able to
learn from the differences and I think
she is probably the best equipped person
to get that done.
Thank you.
My claim is that I believe feminism is
wrongly interpreted as anti-men when it
benefits both men and women. It's a
great claim. I like that claim. Thank
you. Okay. So, I think that in today's
environment, when you look at the
messaging that's coming out from
self-proclaimed feminists, it's very
much an F men, men can't do anything,
women can do bad all by themselves sort
of colloquial messaging, which I think
is harmful to men and to women. I have
seen examples of people that I truly do
think are more old school who don't do
that. Mhm. But I think in 2025 we we've
landed on the side of this it's being it
is I think rising to a level of just
being anti-men which is not what I think
it was supposed to be aspirationally.
Okay. Um in response to that I would
just like to say I think that in all
ideologies and beliefs there is a
spectrum right and and on either side
there's going to be a radical point of
view. I do understand how it may come
across as negative when women say things
like, "I hate all men," or, "F men this,
fen that." But I'm also, as a woman, not
going to fault other women for having
that perspective and fear. Because
unfortunately, our greatest predator is
men. Our greatest harm does come from
men. And therefore, when women have
experienced violence from men, when
women have experienced oppression from
men, I'm not going to fault them for
feeling that way and expressing such.
And I think the onus does rely more on
men for acknowledging that these issues
do exist. It is harming women. And
unfortunately, a lot of men don't listen
to women, and they actually would rather
listen to other men. While that may seem
like negative messaging, if we can get
past the idea of, oh, this feels like
it's attacking my character, like I feel
like feminism is attacking me as a man,
then I think that we can have a much
more productive discussion and move
forward in making sure that this society
is better for everybody. And I do
believe that feminism benefits men as
well. And I think that's also
misunderstood and misinterpreted in that
um when we hear that instantly we turn
off. We don't want to listen, right? But
when we look at historically what
feminism does, it's actually trying to
bring women at an equal level to men,
give them the same opportunities and
options as men and also not receive the
same judgment that men do for the same
actions. And so I believe that when men
are exposed to more female role models,
when men are exposed to more feminine um
or feministleaning women, they actually
have higher quality of life. They have
deeper conversations that they can have
with their loved ones. All the men that
I know in my life are feminists and it
is because they are feminists that we
all have a beautiful community and
beautiful friendships. Yeah. So I would
actually even expand it to say that not
only is feminism hostile to men but it's
also very hostile to women. And I think
you saw a lot of an example of that
today where there seems to be a reaction
when a woman says children are
beautiful. It's like oh my god how how
dare you say that like having a child
and it's like why is there this instant
reaction to people that are traditional?
And you see that when we have a society
which is really kind of being dominated
by what I would call like this hyper
sexual character like of the Kim
Kardashian prototype of feminism weight
against the other extreme which would be
like the Lena Dunham types who are
coming out. Lena Dunham is much more the
Fmen forever. Kim Kardashian is kind of
the when I was saying like come get
everything for free you know that sort
of a model. And I think both of them
reject tradition in a way that there's a
little bit of hatred there for women who
don't want to climb the ladder and work
45 hours a week for a small paycheck and
who actually aspire to marriage. They're
they think that there's something
intrinsically backwards about that. They
think that there's something wrong with
women who are wholesome and happy and
they instantly try to problematize that.
And I'd say one of the greatest cultural
examples of that today was like the
feminist attack on Ballerina Farm, which
just kind of came out of nowhere. It was
so weird. I'm like, we have an example
of every feminist on the cover of
everything. And it's like, but no, this
woman can't have 10 million followers.
She's not allowed to have 10 million
followers. We have to take her down. And
that to me, that to me is the greatest
example of what modern feminism has
become because they pretend it's about
choice, but in reality, they want every
woman to enter the workforce and to
pretend that they're happy in the
workforce from a a 9 toive job trying to
compete with men. And I I think if
people are being honest, the
overwhelming majority of women are doing
that because of financial power, not
because they're really happy and that's
why they're binge drinking on the
weekends. And okay, I disagree with
that. I think that feminism just gives
women options. And if you want to be a
stay-at-home like wife and you want to
be a trad wife, that's fine. Feminism is
not I, in my opinion, and I think a lot
of other people agree with me, feminism
is not the belief that you can't do
those things and we're trying to
convince women that they they have to
work. I believe that feminism is if you
want to work, go do that. Go get that
bag, you know, but if you don't and you
want to be a stay-at-home wife, then
there shouldn't be consequences for
doing that. And I think the whole
ballerina farm discussion is kind of
highlighting some of the consequences.
We see a woman who wanted to be a
ballerina but gave up that passion and
dream to be a mother. And I don't think
that it's wrong to want both. I think
that you can I think there's value in
being a mother. I think there's value in
having a family, right? I work with kids
all the time as a swim teacher. I love
kids. But at the same time, I don't want
to have to choose between kids and my
career path or my project. Choose. And
that's another thing is they just keep
rejecting her answering this question a
thousand times. Of course, when you're
young and before you have kids, the
things that I wanted to do
aspirationally has radically transformed
from now that I'm married, it's suddenly
everything came into focus. And really,
I understand that family is what it's
all about. It's like you have your first
kid and you just you change entirely.
Your focus changes. And I do find
exactly what you're saying is that even
when she herself says, "This is what I
wanted. I was not forced to give up. You
know, that's what I wanted when it was
just me." in my life and I went to
Julliard and I did what I wanted to do
and I danced as a ballerina and then my
husband moved to support me as a
ballerina and then I got pregnant and it
when you have a child your entire world
changes instantly in a moment and it's
hard to describe that to someone who
doesn't have a child yet because when I
was there I didn't understand it either
so I actually would have agreed more
with you until that moment happens you
don't get it um and so what I'm saying
is that to see people constantly try to
problematize her life when she's like I
have eight kids now. It's like not only
do I love kids, I have eight of them and
I'm cooking and I'm going to school and
I'm bringing them with me to Ireland.
And the attacks on the trad culture, it
just shows you that there is
fundamentally a hatred for tradition.
And I think that hatred is being bred
into women. And ultimately when you find
those women at 50 who have chased their
careers, it has been my experience and
they don't have family that they suffer
from tremendous unhappiness if they've
missed that window of opportunity to
start a family. I mean I would like to
disagree with that point that feminism
is hating on the tradife life. I think
there is a misrepresentation of that
life that's being fed to people. For
example, people like Nara Smith and
Ballerina Farm are they are social media
content creators. That is their job,
right? So, it's not that they're just a
stay-at-home mom. Content creation
itself, as I'm sure you're aware, is
also a job, right? So, they are not
actually fully tread wives. They also
are working. And on top of that, they
are marketing this lifestyle that is not
attainable by everybody. It's not
feasible, and I think you agree with
this too, to be spending eight hours
cooking like, I don't know, chocolate
chip cookies from scratch where you've
harvested the cocoa yourself. You know
what I mean? And it's not feasible in
our current economic system, right? And
maybe that's what people want and that's
great. And I don't think feminism is the
one that's telling you you shouldn't
want this. I disagree with that
strongly. I think feminism is telling
you that if you want to pursue that,
that's great. That's for you. I've never
met a feminist who didn't find a problem
with the triedwives. And and that's my
point is that it's this illusion. Well,
you're meeting one now. You're I think I
don't think because as soon as I said
something traditional, everyone
rejected. I said you get more you will
get more purpose and joy from raising a
you get joy from raising a child. And
everyone acted like when I said you get
joy from raising a child like I had
stabbed them in the chest. Like guys,
shouldn't we just like understand that
children are like it's a good children?
I don't think any of us here hate kids.
I think I think the point is it's not
about oh I've mentioned something
traditional and this is the the reaction
that I'm getting from it. It's that it's
almost like you're making an assumption
that this applies to everybody. I I do I
am making a generalization and I am
saying people are reacting to the
majority of women did not invest time to
start a family. Women would be
miserable. And I think that recognizing
that when women start to like the
biological clock is real and women start
to recognize that they spend so much
time trying to climb a ladder and they
maybe don't find a partner and it's
harder to find a partner now because as
I said we have devalued ourselves by
giving up sex so freely. I do see that
there is an increase in those types of
women who are relying on drugs to make
them happy whether they're right but not
not everybody wants marriage and not
everybody wants a relationship.
Overwhelmingly,
women women do want the safety of a
relationship in a happy home. And I
think that feminism lies to you and
tells you that you don't until it's too
late. And that's that is what I do a lot
of work trying to get women to
understand. Yeah. No, and I understand
that you're you're trying I'm sorry. I'm
sorry. That's time. I do apologize.
You have people who are coming because
they want to create a social media
moment. And these are always I've done
so many events the most frustrating
things because nobody's learning. And I
also think it's something that women
that are young need to come to terms
with or they're going to end up on the
other side and be miserable and be
popping pills like a lot of women who
bought into the illusion of feminism
did. So it was frustrating but also
people can see like how many times I
just couldn't was allowed to speak. It
is important to interrupt conservatives
specifically conservatives like Candace
because once you do that their policies
will will show themselves. today. It
felt like one conservative, a 19
cisgender mainstream feminist, and the
weird queer person just kind of hanging
out. We absolutely are part of the
feminist movement, and I hope the the
mainstream gets that one day. I think
that Candace herself is a great example
that you can do both. And when you have
a society and a culture that encourages
women to do what they want, how they
want, in a way that is safe and healthy,
you will see that women can do it all,
as she said, and be happy. I don't think
that you have to choose between having
kids and having a career. And I think
that that is like a fundamentally
misleading
argument.
I guess I would just say we all agree
that sandwiches are good. We just
disagree on who should be making them.